Farming Life in Another World
Now then, time to get today's work started.
What is it, Zabuton?
A bee?!
It's huge.
What are you going to do with it?
Will you eat it?
So then... you'll keep it as a pet?
Yeah, it might be dangerous.
Oh, it won't fight back anymore?
Okay. Got it.
There we go.
I built a little house for
the bee's nest near the orchard.
They built a big nest inside
in about ten days.
The worker bees are all busy
taking care of their jobs.
Queen Bee
By the way, only the queen is that big.
The worker bees are all normal sized.
Worker Bee                                                                      Queen Bee
If I leave them here like this, I wonder if
they'll make honey that I can harvest.
The crops in the fields have
flowering plants, but...
maybe I should plant a flower garden nearby
if I want to be able to harvest honey.
Excuse me, Hiraku...
Pardon the intrusion!
Maybe she's been stung before or something.
What's this?
A reservoir.
Or at least it will be, some day.
I planned on drawing water from
the river through a waterway,
but I've been pretty busy
with other stuff lately.
I see.
How far have you progressed with
the waterway construction?
To be honest, I haven't even
progressed far enough
to decide what I'm going to
make it out of yet.
There's actually quite a bit of distance
between here and the river.
Reservoir
River
First we need to decide
what to build it out of, right?
I've always pictured waterways as
things that you build from stone.
Hm... I think it would be hard to find
stone to work with around here.
So, should we make it out of wood?
Well, we do have a lot of wood here.
But if we have a long waterway, the gaps
in the wood will cause a lot of leakage.
In that case...
We'll use this!
I compacting dirt using
the almighty farming tool.
It's about as hard as concrete.
I think this will work.
Crete?
Never mind.
I actually had a mountain of dirt left over
from digging out the reservoir
that I wasn't sure what to do with.
We went right into mass production mode.
One! Two!
Next one!
We built an intake gate for the water
at the top of the waterfall.
Then we built up the foundation using dirt,
and placed the parts for
the waterway on top of it.
Okay.
A little more this way.
I let the elves handle
the basic foundation work.
Good work.
I focused on sealing the seams and
strengthening the foundation.
Thanks to all of their hard work,
the construction moved along a lot faster
than I was initially expecting.
Now we finally won't have to climb
in and out of the well for water every day.
Yeah. This should make watering
the crops much easier as well.
Oh, look what's here.
I haven't been able to get
my hands on them until now,
but now that we have access to the river,
I'll finally be able to eat fish.
Now I just need to decide
how I'm going to prepare them.
You know, the rabbits in this forest
may be really vicious,
but the fish here seem to be pretty normal.
I'm really glad that they're so easy to catch-
Ah!
Aren't those fish...
from The Forest of Death?
Yeah. Those are the really vicious ones.
I wonder if it's safe to eat those...
Here, it's ready.
Oh, I couldn't.
You should get to eat first
since you made it.
Y-yeah, she's right.
You're the one who made it.
Are you sure?
Okay then, I'll help myself.
It looks and tastes just like salmon.
Like ham and what?
Uh, forget what I said.
Here. Don't be shy, eat up.
This is...
d-delicious!
So, um... would you all like to try some?
They all loved it so I went through
everything I made that time.
But after that we caught a lot
and preserved them with salt
so we could put them away in storage.
I decided to try tilling with the hoe
while thinking about rice plants,
and rice plants popped up.
I didn't know that they could
grow in normal soil,
but now that we have
the waterways built here...
We're building a rice paddy.
Did you say a paddy?
It looks just like a normal crop field...
I'm just getting started here!
Are you building a pond here, too?
Oh, I know!
You're going to keep fish here, right?
I guess that's how it looks now.
Okay, now I'm going to need you all
to help me with this next part.
Huh? What should we do?
It's all slimy.
Okay everyone, I'm going to
hand these seedlings out
and then we're going to plant them.
The girls were a little nervous at first,
but they got the hang of it right away.
The rice planting went off without a hitch.
I put Zabuton's children in charge of
keeping pests out of the area.
I'm not sure if it was thanks to the water
or the almighty farming tool,
but the rice plants grew much faster
than I was expecting them to.
And now, it's time to harvest.
I had Lea and the girls
help me with this, too.
And thanks to them,
it was done in the blink of an eye.
So...
what exactly are we doing now?
We're drying them to get all the moisture out.
You know about all kinds of stuff, don't you?
No, this is just something
I happened to have picked up.
That's right.
I happened to watch an idol
doing this on TV one time.
So, these are the crops
you grew in that paddy?
What are you going to do now?
We're going to thresh them.
Thresh them?
Yup.
Let's see...
I'm pretty sure the old thresher I saw
in a museum looked something like this.
Well, that's the gist of it.
Next, we put them through a sieve to get rid
of any remaining leaves or plant matter.
Then we use a mortar to
remove the husk from the rice.
And now, we use a pestle
to polish the rice.
This stuff takes a lot of work.
Yeah...
Can you not eat it
if you don't do all this?
Are you finally done?
Yeah.
That means we can eat it, right?
No, not yet.
What now?
I'm cooking the rice.
If I remember right, the way to
cook rice in a kettle like this is...
First you start it nice and slow,
then later the sparks fly.
Once it starts rising up,
cut the heat down.
Add a fistful of straw to the fire.
Then no matter what happens,
don't lift the lid.
What kind of spell was that?
Who knows? I've never heard it before.
Hey, Lu.
Could you use your magic
to light the fire?
Sure, I'd be happy to.
It's finally time for the great sage
Lord Lulucy to show what she can do!
I'll blast you to smithereens.
Uh, it's supposed to be nice
and slow so I need a low flame!
Aw, come on. How boring.
I wonder what kind of food
he's making this time.
I'm not sure what he's making,
but I'm curious to see what the spell did.
It came out great!
It's done now, right?
Not yet.
This is what he spent all that time making?
Yeah. If you're going to try rice,
then I think rice balls are the way to go.
After you.
F-fine, I'll do it.
It's delicious!
Glad to hear it.
Hey...
this is the fish from the other day!
Yeah. The saltiness goes well with the rice.
Now I feel like all that hard work
was worth it!
This is my happiest moment as a farmer yet.
Are they good?
W-well, it looks like they're a hit.
I'll just have to work harder
and make more.
Next time I think I'll do a different filling.
Rice Paddy
Reservoir
Let's stop here for today.
Okay.
Apparently, they can all
clean themselves off with magic.
It's times like this I really wish
I had a bath I could hop in.
Well, I did build a waterway,
so I'll give it a shot and build one!
A bath?
Yeah.
What's that?
It's a place where you wash
your body with warm water.
A furnace to heat up the water.
Furnace
A tub to hold the water.
Tub
And a place to wash your body.
Furnace
Tub
Washing Area
I want to make a changing room, too.
Furnace
Tub
Changing Room
Washing Area
Furnace
Tub
Washing Area
Can't we just wash ourselves
in a river or something?
Isn't it too cold for that during the winter?
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Just trust me! Baths are great!
I want to build one, no matter what it takes!
It's good for your circulation
and can improve your health!
W-we'll help you build it.
It's good for your circulation
and can improve your health!
And so, construction began right away.
The furnace was made from blocks of dirt
compacted with the hammer.
We fed it water we brought in
from the waterway.
And the most important part
of the bath, the tub itself.
I want to make it as big as possible.
We made stools to sit on in the washing area.
Everything seems to be going well.
What's wrong?
I'm just now noticing this...
Reservoir
Pulling water from the river is fine and all.
But is it okay to put our wastewater from
the bath and stuff back into the river?
If that's what you're worried about,
we can just use slimes.
Slimes?
Yeah.
They eat waste products and
dead organic matter and purify it.
They're nature's cleaning machines.
Aren't those weak looking monsters
that are actually really dangerous
and end up being the number one
cause of death in new adventurers?
Not at all!
I'll go catch some.
All done.
She grabbed them from
near the starting village.
Will you eat this?
Okay. Got it.
I built a purification pool for the slimes
in the waste-waterway.
If we put slimes in the toilet,
they'll clean everything there for us!
I'm glad they'll do that,
but I don't know if I have the courage to
do my business right above a slime's head.
And just like that,
the wastewater problem was solved.
Now I just need to grab some firewood,
and the bath will be ready to go.
A mushroom...
I've actually been too afraid to eat
any of the mushrooms in this forest
because I don't know which ones
might be poisonous.
You made the right choice.
Researcher's Opinion
They're really hard to tell apart.
They're pretty much edible if you cook them!
Wild Bunch
Extremist
If you'd like me to, I'd be happy to
eliminate them all for you.
Huh? Is that what we're talking about?
The residents all had different opinions.
In that case...
Shiitake, shiitake.
I wanted to hurry up and grow
all the mushrooms I knew.
Shimeji, shimeji.
I'm not sure if this was right way to do it...
Eringi, maitake.
Bunashimeji, shimeji.
I completely forgot about the bath.
Now I'm going to teach you all
how to use the bath.
First, you take your clothes off
in the changing room.
Then, before you actually get into the tub,
you first need to rinse and lightly wash
yourself off in the washing area using a...
Um, excuse me.
It would be very helpful if you could
show us how it's done.
Y-you want me to show you?
Uh, first you get undressed.
Then you rinse yourself.
Then you wash yourself.
Finally, you get into the bath and...
This is the best.
I can really feel it.
How long has it been since I've
taken a bath like this?
I remember I wasn't allowed to get
into a bath while I was hospitalized.
Almost zoned out there.
So anyways, that's how you enjoy the bath...
Okay!
It's nice to be able to relax and
wash ourselves like this.
U-um...
No, it's just that...
I'll get out first, so you all take your time.
Why?
Can't we all just bathe together?
She's right.
This way we don't need to
heat up the water again.
Well, yeah.
You're right about that, but still...
I'm too embarrassed to relax right now.
In the end, there wasn't much time
for me to relax while I was in the bath.
I should have built a separate men's bath.
Wouldn't that just be a private bath for you?
No fair! You can't have one all for yourself.
Is that what you guys think?
Looks like it worked.
Maybe I'll make a mushroom hot pot tonight.
The dogs found five new elves
and brought them here.
I'm Lafa.
I'm Lasa.
I'm Lalasha.
I'm Lalu.
I'm Lami.
You're all La.
Oh, do you mean our names?
The reason our names are similar is...
You're all related, right?
Yes. I'm surprised that you knew that.
Do they all want to live here, too?
Yes. They used to live in
the same village as us.
Since we left, we've been living our lives as
wanderers looking for somewhere to settle.
It's been 200 years since our groups
have seen each other.
200!
You must have had a really rough time.
Okay, it's fine by me.
If you'd like, you can live here with us.
Thank you very much.
Let's start building a house
for you all to live in right away.
I know!
Why don't we take this opportunity to make
some improvements to Hiraku's house as well?
Well, there are more people living in it now.
I guess it is getting kind of cramped in there.
We'll help you with the work!
Thanks. That'll be a big help.
Okay everyone, let's get started on our work!
Yeah!
And to ensure the revival of our race,
let's also start making children!
Yeah!
I'm not sure how they
intend to make children,
but it's nice to see they're so optimistic.
Let's start now!
It's time to make houses!
Yeah, let's go!
Farming Life...
in Another...
World.
...let's also start making children!
Yeah!
It appears the number of females in
my master's pack has increased again.
My name is Kuro.
Before I met my master,
I didn't have a name to call my own.
Starting from the moment I was born;
I spent my whole life in this forest alone.
I never lost a single fight to another male.
I planned on living my whole life
doing whatever I pleased
and hunting when I needed to eat.
But one day...
I met a female.
I didn't stand a chance against her.
After my complete loss to that female,
we began to travel together.
Sometime after that,
her belly started to grow.
It wouldn't be long before
she gave birth to our children.
There are animals in this forest
who lead around packs of their little ones.
When I thought about how that
would become my life one day,
it didn't seem so bad.
But then...
Our luck took a turn for the worse.
We ran into the one they call the
grappler bear, the king of this forest.
I don't know if he decided on a whim
to spare us, or if he was just full,
but he didn't eat us.
We were still gravely injured,
and as a result we couldn't hunt for food.
We'd become so weak that our
former prey had driven us away,
and before we knew it, we found ourselves
at the center of this forest,
at a place where even the grappler bear
doesn't dare to tread.
What we found there was a human male.
I always thought the people living in
the forest kept themselves hidden
and never stayed in one place for too long.
How could someone so weak looking
survive here by himself?
Come on.
How could someone so weak looking
survive here by himself?
It was that.
I felt a limitless power
coming from that tool.
We thought our lives were over,
and we'd already made our peace with that.
But he shared his prey with us.
He took care of us.
This is the meat of a gate boar.
I'm impressed that he was able
to hunt such a great beast.
We don't have any desire to fight him.
The female and I have decided that
this male will be our master.
Our master gave us names
as well as a home to live in.
The meat that he bleeds and cleans for us
and the vegetables he cooks are delicious.
But the most delicious part of
an animal is the innards.
Throwing that away is a terrible waste.
Before long, our children grew up
and our family got bigger.
Our master also become the leader
of a large pack of his own.
Looking at all the females he leads,
I can't help but think that he must be
more than just a weak human
as I'd once thought he was.
My only concern now is,
our master doesn't seem to understand.
He's unaware that we're the terrifying
monsters known as the inferno wolves.
Well, I'm sure it'll be fine.
Right now, I'm just thankful
that my good fortune...
led me here to him.
Next time
Episode 5
Curry and Surviving the Winter